The storm awaits.
Everest is a adventure, drama, history film directed by Baltasar Kormákur.
Inspired by the incredible events surrounding a treacherous attempt to reach the summit of the world's highest mountain, "Everest" documents the
awe-inspiring journey of two different expeditions challenged beyond their limits by one of the fiercest snowstorms ever encountered by mankind.
Their mettle tested by the harshest of elements found on the planet, the climbers will face nearly
impossible obstacles as a lifelong obsession becomes a breathtaking struggle for survival.
Rob Hall, played by Jason Clarke.
Beck Weathers, played by Josh Brolin.
Scott Fischer, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Caroline Mackenzie, played by Elizabeth Debicki.
Jan Arnold, played by Keira Knightley.
Guy Cotter, played by Sam Worthington.
Everest is a 2015 biographical survival film directed and produced by Baltasar
Kormákur and written by William Nicholson and Simon Beaufoy.
It stars an ensemble cast of Jason Clarke, Jake Gyllenhaal, Josh Brolin, John Hawkes, Robin Wright,
Michael Kelly, Sam Worthington, Keira Knightley, Martin Henderson and Emily Watson.
Based on the 1996 Mount Everest disaster in which eight climbers died, it focuses on the survival attempts of
two expedition groups, one led by Rob Hall (Clarke) and the other by Scott Fischer (Gyllenhaal).
Kormákur, Universal Pictures, Walden Media, Cross Creek Pictures and Working Title
Films dedicated the film to the late British actress Natasha Richardson.
The film opened the 72nd Venice International Film Festival on September 2,
2015, and was released theatrically on September 18, 2015.
It was first released in IMAX 3D on September 11, 2015, in the UK and in IMAX 3D, RealD 3D, and 2D internationally, and exclusively
in IMAX 3D, September 19, 2015, as a limited release in the United States and Canada, and along 36 other countries.
It began a wide release in the United States on September 25.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $203 million worldwide against a
$55 million budget and received positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of himalaya mountain range,
mountain, hiking, snowstorm, based on true story.
The tone is uplifting and emotional and intense.